Finding Aid for Center for Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- VHS Videotapes 1971-2004
  - 1996-2004
    - 1996-02-24 East Conference Room Sessions, PM, SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - 1996-02-04 "Across Space and Time," Panel 4, West Conference Room (Box 51)
      (sic. 1996-02-24)
    - 1996-02-24 Lester K Spence, Sarita McCoy Gregory, Olukayode O. Nejo, Hanes Walton, Stephen Broyles, also group discussion, part 1 (Box 51)
    - 1997-10-17 Conference: "Keepin' It Real: Authority and Authenticity in the Performance of African-American Scholarship," Michigan Association of Black Graduate Students, University of Michigan (Box 51)
    - 1998-04-06 African Student's Association African Nights II (Box 52)
    - 2000 Jumah Hamilton, director "HIV/AIDS: Pedagogy in Action: 2000" (Box 52)
      (South Africa Study Abroad 2000) Program Director: Dr. Nesha Haniff, "Time: 50:23" "Tape 1" A second copy, with less metadata on the carrier, is marked "original"
    - 2000-04-29 Black Celebratory Hill Auditorium, "2 hrs." (Box 52)
    - 2001-01 Anointed Men of God Mentor Program, GCBC/Big Brothers Big Sisters, University of Michigan Trip (Box 52)
    - 2001-04-28 University of Michigan Black Celebratory "1 hour, 39 min." (Box 52)
    - 2002-01 Judith Carney, "Rice.," MLK Day Symposium (Box 52)
    - 2004-03-12 Unknown conference
      - Tape 1, 9:14-11am (Box 52)
      - Tape 2, 11am-12:30pm (Box 52)
      - Tape 3, 1:30pm-2:45pm (Box 52)
    - 2004-03-13 Unknown conference
      - Tape 1, 3-4pm (Box 52)
      - Tape 2, 9:15-11:30am (Box 52)
      - Tape 3, 11:30am-12:15pm (Box 52)
      - Tape 4, 3-4pm (Box 52)
- Open Reel Video 1971-1980
  - 1971-03 Val Gray Ward & Co., Part II; Robert Williams, "Community Development, Socialism" and Barbara Ann Teer, "National Black Theatre (Entire Troupe)", 1 hr (Box 53)
  - 1973-04-12 "Seminar on King Christophe and the Negritude Movement" (Box 53)
    (Tape 1, 1/2 hrs)
  - 1973-04-19 NCA, Elma Lewis, "Preserving Our Culture" (Box 53)
  - 1979-03-01 Robert Williams, "Black Activism and Black Politics," Part I (Box 53)
  - 1979-03-01 Robert Williams, "Black Activism and Black Politics," Part II (Box 53)
  - 1979-03-01 James Turner, "Black Studies: Retrospect and Prospect" (complete tape)1979-03-01 -- James Turner, "Black Studies: Retrospect and Prospect," Part III and M. Ron Karenga, "The Fundamental Crisis in Black Life: Analysis and Alternatives" Part I (Box 53)
  - 1979-03-01 M. Ron Karenga, "The Fundamental Crisis in Black Life: Analysis and Alternatives" Part II (Box 53)
  - 1980-03-20 Panel, "The Organizations and Significance of BAM," Part I of 3, "Attn Cynthia Stevens, Attn Ron Harris, Attn David Lewis, Prof. Niara Sudarkasa" 1:30-3:30 (Box 53)
  - 1980-03-20 Smith, Varner, Hefner, Mann, Yates, Panel, "Perspectives on BAM from the University Community," 4:00pm (Part I) (Box 53)
  - 1980-03-20 Smith, Varner, Hefner, Mann, Yates, Panel, "Perspectives on BAM from the University Community," 4:00pm (Part II) and Panel: "The Challenge of BAM for the 1980s" 5:30pm (Part I) (Box 53)
    Available on cassette
  - 1980-03-20 Jemadari Kamara, Ben Newhouse, Vicky Rowels, Virna Hobbs, Janice O'Neal, Obika Gray, Panel, "The Challenge of BAM for the 1980s (Box 53)
    (5:30-7:70pm (Part II) Available on cassette)
  - 1980-03-21 Howard Shapiro, "UM: A Decade After BAM" and Panel: "The Organization and Significance of BAM", 2 videotapes VHS [TM] (Box 53)
    (The title of the talk and panel was obtained from a cassette recording of the same)
- Reel-to-reel audiotape 1971, 1980
  - undated Harold Cruse, Leroi Jones, Jimmy Garrett (Interviews) (Box 54)
  - 1971-03 Harold Cruse; "On the Significance of Black Culture," Black Liberation Week (Box 54)
    (Part I only, Monday)
  - 1971-03-17 Side I: Jimmy Garrett and Phil Lee, Community Center Side II: Robert Williams and James V. Turner, undated (Box 54)
    (Side 1 event May also be documented on a U-Matic Video, and on open reel video;)
  - 1980-02-24 "Tribute to Robert Hayden," Parts I, II and III, Stearns Building, University of Michigan, WUOM (Box 54)
    (3 reels)
    (These available on cassettes)
- Mini DVDs 1999-2000
  - Undated SAIO Awards ceremony (Box 54)
  - Undated Interview with Nozizwe M. Routledge (Box 54)
  - 1999-02-17 Moody Training Program Lecture 3 (Box 54)
  - Undated, circa 1999-2003 Teshome Wagaw, Lecture 4, tape 1 (Box 54)
  - 1999-03-17 Lecture 6 (Box 54)
  - 01 -- 2000-07-04 Bernadette and friend guest lecture in Johannesburg., 1 hour (Box 54)
  - 02 -- 2000-06-30-2000-07-02 Safari trip, God's Window, and pot holes. (Box 54)
  - 03 -- 2000-07-04 Sumah and Sam teach soccer team., 35 minutes (Box 54)
  - 04 -- circa 2000-06-09 Interviews with group to find out how first 3 weeks were in S. Africa. (Box 54)
  - 05 -- 2000-07-05 Mr(s?) Moffat (Box 54)
  - 06 -- First interviews: Dr. Moody, Prof. Haniff, Latonia, Julie, Betsy before the trip (Box 54)
  - 07 -- Interviews: Jumah, Lesley (Box 54)
  - 08 -- Interviews: Alexi, Kyle, Elizabeth, Jumah (1/2) (Box 54)
  - 09 -- 2000-05-24 Second interviews a week before the S. Africa trip: Rashad, Hilary, Phyllis, Sabrina, Diana (Box 54)
  - 10 -- 2000-03-10-South Africa meeting no. 3 (Box 54)
  - 11 -- Chris Hani (Hari?) teaches back; presentation of certificates; listing to President (Box 54)
  - Mbeki's speech on TV. (Box 54)
  - 12 -- Les and Sabrina, Maguboni(?) and Daisy (2 of 2) (Box 54)
  - 13 -- Jumah and Kyle cptn; Lesley and Sabrina; traditional healers (1 of 2) (Box 54)
  - 14 -- Traditional healers presentation; Leslie and Sabrina (Box 54)
  - 15 -- Langa(?) Certificate presentations (Box 54)
  - 16 -- untitled (Box 54)
  - 17 -- untitled (Box 54)
  - 18 -- untitled (Box 54)
  - 19 -- Ms illegible Braii(?) (Xhosa) (Box 54)
Related Material
Related collections at the Bentley Library include the papers of CAAS faculty members
Lemuel A. Johnson
,
Ali A. Mazrui
and
Willis C. Patterson
. The collections of choral director
Eva Jessye
, bandleader
Andy Kirk
, and of baritone
Todd Duncan
were transferred from the CAAS library to the Bentley in 2008.